Guide to the Andover Newton Faculty Publications Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Individuals A-L, Series I
  - Ferré, Nels Frederick Solomon
    - "Spirit of Christmas Eternal." The Hillview 24/3 (December 1960): 6. (Box 30)
    - The Atonement and Mission. Essay on Mission, no. 2. London: London Missionary Society, 1960. (Box 30)
    - Toward Spiritual Renewal: The Individual, The Family, The Church. Nashville: The Upper Room, 1962. (Box 30)
    - "Theologians of Our Time: IX. The Theology of Gustaf Aulén." Expository Times 74/11 (Aug. 1963): 324-327. (Box 30)
    - Biblical Faith and Philosophic Truth: Dedicatory Address at the Service of the Dedication of the Frank Halliday Ferris Chair of Philosophy. Wooster, OH: College of Wooster, 1964. (Box 30)
    - "Beyond Substance and Process." Theology Today 24/2 (July 1967): 160-171. (Box 30)
    - "The Place of the Chapel in a Christian College." Journal of Higher Education 38/4 (Apr. 1967): 177-183. (Box 30)
    - Assorted Bibliographies of Ferré, Nels Frederick Solomon, no date (Box 30)
  - Fontaine, Carol R.
    - Traditional Sayings in the Old Testament: A Contextual Study. Sheffield, England: Almond Press, 1982. (Box 31)
    - "Finding a voice." Centering 3 (Winter 1986): 12-16. (Box 31)
    - "Does Jacob deserve prime time?" Biblicon: The Journal of Bible in Media and Culture 1 (Spring 1997): 35-42. (Box 31)
    - "Tricksters in the Bible." Witness 81/7-8 (July-August 1998): 8-10. (Box 31)
    - Smooth words: women, proverbs and performance in biblical wisdom. New York: Sheffield Academic Press, 2002. (Box 31)
    - With Eyes of Flesh: The Bible, gender and human rights. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008 (Box 31)
    - Advent Worship Companion: Lectionary Year C. United States of America: LuLu.com, 2009. (Box 32)
    - Only When Women Sing: Poems on Human Rights. United States of America: LuLu.com, 2009. (Box 32)
    - Companion to Thematic Introduction to Latter Prophets and Writings: References, Readings and Assignments. Ed. Jennifer Shaw. Greenheart Studio by Lulu Publishing, 2012. (Box 32)
    - Claiming the Psalms: A Guide for Readers, Students, and Believers. Ed. Jennifer Shaw. Greenheart Studio by Lulu Publishing, 2016. (Box 32)
    - Bibliography of Fontaine, Carol R., no date (Box 32)
    - Curriculum Vitae of Fontaine, Carol R., no date (Box 32)
  - Gates, Owen H.
    - A Minister's Reading. Andover, 1908. (Box 33)
  - Gezork, Herbert Johannes
    - "Wenn Ich ein Prediger wäre." [no publication information], 1922 (Box 34)
    - Die Baptistische Aussassung von Religioser Freiheit." [no publication information], 1923 (Box 34)
    - "Eine zeitgemä Anwendung der Bergpredigt." [no publication information], 1925 (Box 34)
    - "Unsere Wartburgsahrt." [no publication information], 1926 (Box 34)
    - Unsere Jüngerschaft und Unser Zeugendienst im Blick auf die Gottlosenbewegung. Kassel: J. G. Oncken Nachf., 1932. (Box 34)
    - "Isms and Facts Behind Europe's Headlines." (radio address delivered before the Sunday Morning Men's Class, Waterville, ME, January 7, 1940) (Box 34)
    - "Youth Faces A New World." The American Friend (November 21, 1940): 498-499. (Box 34)
    - "From International Anarchy to a World Community. Wellesley Magazine 26/2 (December 1941): 68-69. (Box 34)
    - "Youth and Tomorrow's World." First Baptist Courier (Dayton, OH) 9/35 (May 29, 1941). (Box 34)
    - "God in Hitler's Germany." The Baptist Student 31/5 (February 1942): 5-6. (Box 34)
    - "Our Strongest Weapon—Faith." Wellesley Magazine 26/4 (April 1942): 204. (Box 34)
    - "Religion, the War and the Peace." [no publication information], 1942 (Box 34)
    - "The Head of the Church … In Stimulating Its Aspirations." The Christian Advocate (January 15, 1942): 80-81. (Box 34)
    - "International Round Table of Christian Leaders at Princeton." (Report for the Postwar Planning Commission of the Northern Baptist Convention), 1943 (Box 34)
    - "Paganism in Modern Dress." Challenge 2/2 (April/May/June 1943): 10-12. (Box 34)
    - "Commencement Address." [ Dana Hall Bulletin (July 1944): 3-5.] (Box 34)
    - "What Hope for Germany's Youth—After Hitler?" [no publication information], 1944 (Box 34)
    - "Germany's Youth After Hitler." Friends Intelligencer (Second Month 3, 1945): 69-71. (Box 34)
    - "Review of Race and Crime, by Willem Adrian Bonger." Crozer Quarterly (January 1945): 91-92. (Box 34)
    - "Shadows and Light in War Ravaged Germany." Missions (December 1945): 524-29. (Box 34)
    - "Shadows and Light in War Ravaged Germany." The Religious Digest (January 1946): 76-82. (Box 34)
    - "Review of The Reconstruction of Humanity, by Pitirim A. Sorokin." [no publication information], 1948 (Box 34)
    - "The Obligations of the Privileged: Baccalaureate sermon delivered at Bradford Junior College, [June 6 and 7, 1948]." Bulletin of Bradford Junior College [no other publication information] (Box 34)
    - "Today and Tomorrow in Postwar Germany." Missions (October 1948): 474-77. (Box 34)
    - "Today and Tomorrow In Postwar Germany." Zions Herald 76 (October 13, 1948): 963-65. (Box 34)
    - "Review of Religious Liberty, by Cecil Northcott." [no publication information], 1949 (Box 34)
    - "The Revived Society of Inquiry." Missions (May 1950): 293-94. (Box 34)
    - "God Is Love." Boston Traveler (March 6, 1951). (Box 34)
    - "Heiligabend unter Kulis und Vagabunden." Evangelisches Gemeindeblatt., 1951 (Box 34)
    - "Review of The Christian in Politics, by Jerry Voorhis." [no publication information], 1951 (Box 34)
    - "Religion Under Totalitarianism." The Christian Leader (March 1952): 75-77, 84-87. (Box 34)
    - "Review of Religion and the Decline of Capitalism, by V.A. Demant." [no publication information], 1952 (Box 34)
    - "The Fate of Religion Under Totalitarianism." Zions Herald (March 5, 1952): 225-27, 236. (Box 34)
    - So Sah Ich Die Welt: Aus Einem Weltreise-Tagebuch. Kassel, Germany: J. G. Oncken Nachfolger, 1952. (Box 34)
    - "Christians in a Struggle for World Community." Crusader (October, 1954). (Box 34)
    - "Review of Religion and Freedom of Thought, by Perry Miller, Robert L. Calhoun, Nathan M. Pusey, and Reinhold Niebuhr." [no publication information], 1954 (Box 34)
    - "The Fate of Religion under Totalitarianism." Wheaton Alumni Magazine (January 1954): 13-19. (Box 34)
    - "Baptist Unity." The Watchman-Examiner (June 30, 1955): 627-8. (Box 34)
    - "In His Presence." The Watchman-Examiner (September 15, 1955): 833-34. (Box 34)
    - "Unser baptistischer Glaube." Die Gemeinde (October 2, 1955): 308-10. (Box 34)
    - "Dedicatory Address at St. John's Baptist Church, Philadelphia, PA" (February 17, 1956). (Box 34)
    - "Four Historic Baptist Distinctives." The Kansas Baptist (February 1956): 3. (Box 34)
    - "Review of The Church in Soviet Russia, by Matthew Spinka (Dec. 28, 1956)." [no publication information] (Box 34)
    - "Soviet Union" Missions (May 1956): 41-42. (Box 34)
    - "What I Saw in Russia!" Baptist Herald 34 (May 31, 1956):8-9, 22. (Box 34)
    - "What we saw and heard in Soviet Russia." Advance (May 16, 1956): 4-6, 28. (Box 34)
    - "Between the Pulpit Committee and God." Bulletin of Crozer Theological Seminary 48 (October 1956): 3,7., 1957 (Box 34)
    - "Can We Still Believe in a God of Love?" The Pulpit :12-13,16. [no other publication information], 1957 (Box 34)
    - "Review of A Faith for the Nations, by Charles W. Forman." The Westminster Bookman 16 (December 1957):2-3. (Box 34)
    - "Review of Making Ethical Decisions, by Howard Clark Kee." The Westminster Bookman 16 (December 1957):3-4. (Box 34)
    - "That Light Be Not Darkness." (Commencement Address, Vanderbilt University, June 2, 1957) (Box 34)
    - "The Valley of Baca." The Maritime Baptist (December 25, 1957). (Box 34)
    - "Why I Am a Baptist." [no publication information], 1957 (Box 34)
    - Can We and Why? [no publication information], 1957 (Box 34)
    - "Frauenschicksal in Indien." In Wovon Lebt Der Mensch?; ein Vorlesebuch für die Jugend. Vol. 1. Göttingen: Vandenhoek & Ruprecht, 1958. (Box 34)
    - "Review of Ethics and United States Foreign Policy, by Ernest LeFever." The Chaplain (June 1958): 35. (Box 34)
    - "Weinacht Unter Vagabunden." In Wovon Lebt Der Mensch?; ein Vorlesebuch für die Jugend. Vol. 1. Göttingen: Vandenhoeck & Ruprecht, 1958. (Box 34)
    - "Amerikanisches Christentum." In Wovon Lebt Der Mensch?; ein Vorlesebuch für die Jugend. Vol. 2. Göttingen: Vandenhoeck & Ruprecht, 1959. (Box 34)
    - "Die Mission Des Einsamen Sterns." In Wovon Lebt Der Mensch?; ein Vorlesebuch für die Jugend. Vol 2. Gottingen: Vandenhoeck & Ruprecht, 1959. (Box 34)
    - "Mr. Globetrotter Und die Missionare." In Wovon Lebt Der Mensch?; ein Vorlesebuch für die Jugend. Vol. 2. Gottingen: Vandenhoeck & Ruprecht, 1959. (Box 34)
    - "Our Baptist Faith in Today's World." 1959 Annual of the North American Baptist Church [no other publication information] (Box 34)
    - "Review of Outside the Camp: the Christian and the World, by Charles C. West." [no publication information], 1959 (Box 34)
    - "The Future Belongs to Freedom." The Watchman-Examiner (October 8, 1959):818-20. (Box 34)
    - "A Threefold Look for the New Year" Missions (January 1960): 17. (Box 34)
    - "Review of The German Phoenix, by Franklin H. Littell." [no publication information], 1960 (Box 34)
    - Public address at the Pastors' Conference WMU Convention Miami Beach, May 16-17, 1960. (Box 34)
    - "Position Paper on Peace with Justice." Crusader (April 1964): 7. (Box 34)
    - "Human Suffering and Divine Love." The Christian Pulpit (January 1965): 4343-44, 68. (Box 34)
    - "Toward Death or Renewal." Mission (December 1968):18-19. (Box 34)
    - Sermon delivered at Shadyside Presbyterian Church in Pittsburgh, PA on October 26, 1969. (Box 34)
    - "Our Christian Witness in an Age of Revolutions." The Canadian Baptist. [no other publication information], 1970 (Box 34)
    - "Review of The Technological Threat, ed. by Jack D. Douglas." [no publication information], 1971 (Box 34)
    - A Series of Chautauqua Sermons delivered in Chautauqua, NY on August 5 – 10, 1973. (Box 34)
    - "Address at the Inauguration of a new President at Bucknell University." Bucknell World (November 1976). (Box 34)
    - "Review of Just and Unjust Wars by Michael Walzer." The New Review of Books and Religion [no other publication information], 1978 (Box 34)
    - "Christ the Great Internationalist." [no publication information], no date (Box 34)
    - "Friedrich Gottlieb Klopstock." [no publication information], no date (Box 34)
    - Assorted unitemized, undated items., no date (Box 34)
    - Curriculum Vitae and Bibliography of Gezork, Herbert Johannes., no date (Box 34)
  - Gill-Austern, Brita L.
    - "Responding to a culture ravenous for soul food." Journal of Pastoral Theology (Summer 1997): 63-79. (Box 33)
    - Curriculum Vitae and Bibliography of Gill-Austern, Brita L., no date (Box 33)
  - Gilmour, Samuel MacLean
    - The Rise of Church Consciousness Among Early Christians: a part of a dissertation submitted to the faculty of the divinity school in candidacy for the degree of doctor of philosophy. Chicago: The University of Chicago Libraries, 1937. (Box 35)
    - "How relevant is the ethic of Jesus?" Journal of Religion 21 (July 1941): 253-264. (Box 35)
    - "Interpreting the Sermon on the Mount." Crozer Quarterly 24 (January 1947): 47-56. (Box 35)
    - "A critical re-examination of proto-Luke." Journal of Biblical Literature 67 (part II, 1948): 143-152. (Box 35)
    - "The Christmas story in the New Testament." Children's Religion (December 1959). [also reprinted in pamphlet form] (Box 35)
    - "The Easter story in the New Testament." Children's Religion (March 1960). [also reprinted in pamphlet form] (Box 35)
    - "The Christophany to more than five hundred brethren." Journal of Biblical Literature 80 (1961): 248-252. (Box 35)
    - "Easter and Pentecost." Journal of Biblical Literature 81 (March 1962): 62-66. (Box 35)
    - "Jesus Christ." In Dictionary of the Bible, ed. James Hastings; rev. ed. By Frederick C. Grant and H.H. Rowley, 477-496. N.Y.: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1963. (Box 35)
    - "Review of Paul: The Theology of the Apostle in the Light of Jewish Religious History, by H. J. Schoeps." The Journal of Bible and Religion [no volume number], [no date]. (Box 35)
    - "Review of Worship in the New Testament, by Gerhard Delling." [No publication information or date]., no date (Box 35)
    - "The Bible of the early church." The Iliff Review 7 (Spring 1950): 50-58. (Box 35)
    - The Gospel Jesus Preached. Philadelphia: Westminster Press, 1957. (Box 35)
  - González, Justo L.
    - "Hacia un Reduscubrimiento de Nuestra Misión." Apuntes 7/3 (Fall/Otoño 1987): 51-60. (Box 33)
  - Gottwald, Norman Karol
    - "Historical and Constructive Analyses of Baptist Worship: An outline of two articles by Paul Rowntree Clifford." (Box 35)
    - "A sleep of prisoners." Worldview 7 (November 1964): 5-7 (Box 35)
    - "Is nuclear deterrence morally defensible?" (Recorded for War/Peace Spotlight on WBCN-FM, Boston)., no date (Box 35)
    - A Light to the Nations. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1959. (Box 35)
  - Griffin, Benjamin
    - "The Shape of Ministry to Come" (unpublished sermon delivered at Springfield Pastors Conference), 1997 (Box 33)
    - "The Church for the Sake of the World" (unpublished sermon delivered at Metropolitan Boston Association, UCC)., 1997 (Box 33)
    - "Diversity within Unity" (unpublished sermon delivered at Essex Association, UCC), 1997 (Box 33)
    - "Mercersburg and Church Order: Missed Opportunities in the Formation of the United Church of Christ." New Mercersburg Review 22 (Autumn 1997): 60-70. (Box 33)
    - Curriculum Vitae of Griffin, Benjamin., no date (Box 33)
  - Griffin, Edward Dorr
    - A Farewell Sermon, Preached May 28, 1809, at Newark. Newark: Printed by E.B. Gould, 1809. (Box 33)
    - A Sermon on the Art of Preaching, Delivered Before the Pastoral Association in Boston, May 25, 1825. Boston: Printed by T.R. Marvin, 1825. (Box 33)
  - Guardiola-Sáenz, Leticia A.
    - "Maria Magdalena: Apostol a los apostoles," in Camino a Emaus: Compartiendo el ministerio de Jesus. Minneapolis: Fortress Press, 2002. (Box 33)
    - "Forward," in The Upper Room Disciplines. [date and volume unclear], no date (Box 33)
  - Gulliver, John Putnam
    - "An Introductory Essay to Wood's Bible Animals" In Bible Animals. New York: Charles Scribner and Company, 1870. (Box 36)
    - Christianity and Science: An Address by JPG at His Inauguration as Stone Professor of Relations of Christianity to the Secular Sciences. Andover: W.F. Draper, 1880. (Box 36)
    - "A Symposium on Evolution. Is the Darwinian Theory of Evolution Reconcilable with the Bible? If so, with what limitations?" Homiletic Monthly (July 1884): 591-97. (Box 36)
  - Guptill, Nathanael M.
    - Christianity Does Make Sense: A Popular Guide to the Christian Faith for the Layman, the Young People's Sunday School Class, the Bible Study Group. New York: The American Press, 1956. (Box 36)
    - How To Be A Pastor In a Mad, Mod World. St. Louis: Bethany Press, 1970. (Box 36)
  - Hackett, Horatio Balch
    - Illustrations of Scripture, Suggested by a Tour Through the Holy Land. Boston: Heath & Graves, 1855. (Box 37)
    - A Commentary on the Original Text of the Acts of the Apostles. New Edition, revised and enlarged. Boston: Gould and Lincoln, 1858. (Box 37)
    - "On Revision. Remarks before the American Bible Union at Its Tenth Anniversary, New York, October 6, 1859." [no publication information] (Box 37)
    - Illustrations of Scripture, Suggested by a Tour Through the Holy Land. Boston: Heath & Graves, 1860. (Box 37)
    - Christian Memorials of the War. Boston: Gould and Lincoln, 1864. (Box 38)
    - Rawlinson G. Historical Illustrations of the Old Testament. With additions by H.B.H. Boston: Henry A. Young and Co., Boston: Henry A. Young and Co, 1874. (Box 38)
    - Dr. William Smith's Dictionary of the Bible: comprising its antiquities, biography, geography, and natural history, Volume 2: Gennesaret to Market. Co-edited with William Smith and Ezra Abbot. Cambridge, Boston: Houghton, Mifflin and Company, The Riverside Press, 1883. (Box 38)
    - Prof. H.b. Hackett, D.d: Scholar, Interpreter, Teacher: an Address. Place of publication not identified: publisher not identified, 1875. (Box 39)
    - Dr. William Smith's Dictionary of the Bible: comprising its antiquities, biography, geography, and natural history, Volume 3: Marriage to Regem. Co-edited with William Smith and Ezra Abbot. Cambridge, Boston: Houghton, Mifflin and Company, The Riverside Press, 1883. (Box 39)
    - Dr. William Smith's Dictionary of the Bible: comprising its antiquities, biography, geography, and natural history: Volume1: A to Gennesaret, Land of. Co-edited with William Smith and Ezra Abbot. Cambridge, Boston: Houghton, Mifflin and Company, The Riverside Press, 1883. (Box 39)
  - Handspicker, Meredith Brook "Jerry"
    - "Clinical Pastoral Education and Theology." Theological Education and Coinical Pastoral Training Institute of Pastoral Care Fall 1962 Conference, 1962. (Box 40)
    - "Survey of Church Union Negotiations 1961–1963." The Ecumenical Review 16/4 (July 1964): 3-40. (Box 40)
    - "All in Each Place." Study Encounter 1/1 (1965): 3-11. (Box 40)
    - "Truth and Renewal." Crux 68/2 (April-May 1965): 4-5. (Box 40)
    - "Seventh-Day Adventism." World Council of Churches Division of Studies: Commission on Faith and Order FO/66: 19 (March 1966). (Box 40)
    - "Survey of Church Union Negotiations 1963–1965." The Ecumenical Review 18/3 (July 1966): 345-385. (Box 40)
    - "Presentacion." El Boletin 31/3 (July-September 1966). (Box 40)
    - "Grandchildren, Meet Your Grandparents." The Ecumenical Review 19/1 (January 1967): 104-108. (Box 40)
    - "An ecumenical exercise." Edited by MBH and Lukas Vischer. Faith and Order Papers, 49. Geneva: World Council of Churches, 1967. (Box 40)
    - "Review of The Shape of Christology by John McIntyre." Bulletin of The Department of Theology of the World Alliance of Reformed Churches + The World Presbyterian Alliance 8/1 (Autumn 1967): 12–14. (Box 40)
    - "Beziehungen Zwischen Dem Ökumenischen Rat Der Kirchen Und Der Kirche Der Siebenten-Tags-Adventisten." Ökumenische Rundschau. 17.1 (1968): 60-62. (Box 40)
    - "Theologize." Colloquy 2 (July-August 1969): 21-22. (Box 40)
    - "Kirchenumiomen und die zukunft." In Die Unierten Kirchen. ed. John Webster Grant, 341-364. Stuttgart: Evangelisches Verlagswerk, 1973. (Box 40)
    - [Various case studies.] [No publication information.] Boston: The Case Study Institute, 1973-1975. (Box 40)
    - "The Boston affirmation." Boston Industrial Mission Task Force. Boston: Boston Industrial Mission, 1976. (MBH was part of task force which drafted this statement.) (Box 40)
    - "Curricula, accreditation and ordination."Theological Education 12 (Spring 1976): 191-194. (Box 40)
    - "The Importance of Spirituality for Clinical Practice." An address given to the Annual Conference of the Harvard Center for Addiction Studies, Park Plaza Hotel, Boston, Massachusetts, March 9, 1990. (Box 40)
    - "Celebration of the Andover Heritage." TMs (photocopy). Special Collections, Franklin Trask Library, Andover Newton Theological School, Newton, MA., 1990 (Box 40)
    - "What is Spiritual, Anyway?" Massachusetts Council on Compulsive Gambling Newsletter Special Edition (January 1993). (Box 40)
    - "Review of Belonging to the Universe, by Fritjof Capra and David Steindl-Rast with Thomas Matus." CTNS Bulletin 13/1 (Winter 1993): 37-39. (Box 40)
    - "Reader Response." Prism: A Theological Forum For The United Church Of Christ. 8/2 (Fall, 1993): 3. (Box 40)
    - "Ecumenicism." The American People's Encyclopedia. New York, [no date]. (Box 40)
    - "Peter Taylor Forsyth: Free Church Theologian." Reading Guide for Ministers, 1/3 ([no date available]). (Box 40)
    - "Suffering into Unity." [no publication information.], no date (Box 40)
  - Harrelson, Walter
    - "Guide to the Old Testament." ( Andover Newton Waymarks )., no date (Box 33)
    - "The Dead Sea Scrolls.", no date (Box 33)
    - "The Theological School in the Free Church Tradition.", no date (Box 33)
    - "The Word of Life in Living Language.", no date (Box 33)
  - Harris, George
    - The Rational and Spiritual Verification of Christian Doctrine: An Inagural Address delivered June 13, 1883. Andover: Warren F Draper, 1883. (Box 41)
    - Hymns of the Faith with Psalms for the use of Congregations. Cambridge: The Riverside Press, 1887. (Box 41)
    - Moral Evolution. Cambridge: The Riverside Press, 1896. (Box 41)
    - Inequality and Progress. Cambridge: The Riverside Press, 1899. (Box 41)
  - Harris, Maria
    - THE D.R.E. BOOK: QUESTIONS AND STRATEGIES FOR PARISH PERSONNEL. New York: Paulist Press, 1976. (Box 42)
    - "Pastoral team program." In CHANGE MY HEART: A LENTEN PROGRAM. New York: Paulist Press, 1977: 335-338. (Box 42)
    - "Review of Evangelization and Catechesis - Are We Really Proclaiming the Gospel? By Johannes Hofinger." Religious Media Today (Spring/Summer 1977): 15. (Box 42)
    - THEOLOGIANS AND CATECHISTS IN DIALOGUE: THE ALBANY FORUM. ed. Brennan Hill and Mary Reed Newland. Dubuque, IA: Brown, 1977. (Box 42)
    - "Health and holiness: See `Kailo' in the appendix." THE ALTERNATIVE NEWSLETTER 4 (May 1978): 2. (Box 42)
    - "I said to the artist: teach me to pray." THE ALTERNATIVE NEWSLETTER 5 (September 1978): 2-3. (Box 42)
    - "Memorandum to: DREs and parish coordinators...re: issues to be faced in the future." THE CATECHIST 12 (November/December 1978): 3-5. (Box 42)
    - "The future of the profession from a Catholic perspective." PARISH RELIGIOUS EDUCATION. ed. Maria Harris. New York: Paulist Press, 1978. (Box 42)
    - PARISH RELIGIOUS EDUCATION. ed. Maria Harris. New York: Paulist Press, 1978. (Box 42)
    - "Tensions for the teaching pastor." RELIGIOUS EDUCATION 74 (March-April 1979): 47-158. (Box 42)
    - "The justice curriculum: yes, maybe and not at all." THE ALTERNATIVE NEWSLETTER 6 (September 1979): 4-5. (Box 42)
    - "Prayer and the political order." THE ALTERNATIVE NEWSLETTER 6 (December 1979): 5-7. (Box 42)
    - "On silences." THE ALTERNATIVE NEWSLETTER 6 (May 1980): 2-3. (Box 42)
    - "The ministry of forgiveness." In SEVENTY TIMES SEVEN. Kansas City, KS: 1980. (Box 42)
    - THE DRE READER: A SOURCEBOOK IN EDUCATION AND MINISTRY. ed. Maria Harris. Winona, MN: St. Mary's Press, 1980. (Box 42)
    - "Political ministry and the claim to power." NEW CATHOLIC WORLD (January-February 1981): 25-28. (Box 42)
    - "Of clay and clowning." THE ALTERNATIVE NEWSLETTER 7 (February 1981): 2-3. (Box 42)
    - 1981 Draft of "Questioning lay minstry." In WOMEN AND RELIGION: A READER FOR THE CLERGY. ed. Regina Coll. New York: Paulist Press, 1982. (Box 42)
    - PORTRAIT OF YOUTH MINISTRY. New York: Paulist Press, 1981. (Box 42)
  - Hazelton, Roger
    - "Factors in Fellowship." The Chicago Theological Seminary Register 23/4 (November 1933): 9-10. (Box 43)
    - "Tradition and Tomorrow." The Chicago Theological Seminary Register 24/2 (March 1934): 19-21. (Box 43)
    - "Discussion on Hartman's Doctrine of Values as Essences: A Condensed Portion of a Dissertation for the Ph.D. Degree at Yale University." The Philosophical Review 48 (November 1939): 621-632. (Box 43)
    - "The Two Humanisms." Religion in the Making 2/1 (November 1941): 20-38. (Box 43)
    - "Was Nietzsche an Anti-Christian?" The Journal of Religion 22/1 (January 1942): 63-88. (Box 43)
    - "Daniel Day Williams." Advance (November 1943): 10-11. (Box 43)
    - "Toward a Valid Sacramentalism." Christendom 9:2 (Spring 1944): 226-235. (Box 43)